W: greghogan.uk

E: hire@greghogan.uk

L: Zürich, Switzerland





Frontend Developer

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Archlet AG – Frontend developer

Jun 2021 - Present

Frontend developer working with a mix of React, Redux and GraphQL to create a best-in-class Sourcing tool and analysis dashboard. Main responsibilities include creating components for an internal component library as well as developing complex features for in-depth creation of sourcing tables and client questionnaires as well as detailed tables and graphs for analysis.

React, Redux, GraphQL, Styled components, JavaScript.

Exeon Analytics AG (60%) - Senior frontend developer

Feb 2021 - Jun 2021

Senior frontend developer working with a mix of React and Redux building a security network analysis dashboard of graphs and data tables to help identify network intrusions and suspect network behaviour. Main responsibilities, polishing front end features developed by backend developers, creating a component library and style guide for the whole UI.

• React, Redux, Styled components, JavaScript.

Geeiq (40%) - Senior frontend developer

May 2020 - Jun 2021

Senior frontend developer working with Ember and Ember Data, building a data dashboard with graphs and data tables for marketeers to determine appropriate esports streamers for their brand. Main responsibilities of developing new features as well as establishing a style guide and creating a reusable component library.

• Ember.js, Ember CLI, Ember Data, JavaScript, Sass.

Loveholidays - Frontend developer

Nov 2018 - May 2020

Sub-team lead Frontend developer working among a velocity focused team as a part of the "experiments team". Using technologies such as ReactJS, Redux, React Hooks, and styled components to AB test variations of UI elements as well as UX journeys based on designs from the design team.

- ReactJS (Hooks, Styled Components), Redux, Redux-Saga, Immutable.JS,
 MochaJS, Enzyme, Jest, Chai assertion library, Sass, JavaScript, Optimizely.
- Created numerous UI components to aid in standardising page layout as well as recurring UI elements such as iconography, titles, etc.
- Helped to refactor numerous components in regard to JavaScript and HTML markup with an eye to improving readability and efficiency.

SKILLS

Programming and technical

HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Sass, ReactJS (Hooks, Styled Components), Ember.js (Ember CLI, Ember Data, MochaJS, Enzyme, Chai assertion library, NPM, Yarn, Gulp, Webpack, UI / UX design

Experience with

AngularJS, Redux, Redux-Saga, TypeScript, GraphQL

Source control and user experience optimisation software

Git, GitHub, Jenkins, JIRA, Trello, Fullstory, Optimizely

Graphics software

Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Figma, Final Cut Pro

Soft skills

Team lead, project management, interpersonal skills, keen eye for detail

Movidiam Ltd - Senior Frontend developer

Sep 2013 - Apr 2014 (Freelance) / Dec 2014 - Jun 2018

Senior Frontend developer managing a small team. Liaising daily with the product owner, back-end development team and design team for a component based social networking / project management web app with 17K+ users.

- Sass, Ember.js, Ember CLI, Ember Data, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Revamped the HTML markup to modern semantic standards, implemented Sass and established codebase linting.
- Led a small team of developers working within an Agile development process with daily scrums and retrospectives.
- Worked with the design team to vet designs against potential web technology limitations as well as helped transition these designs to a responsive layout.
- Created page templates for Salesforce which integrated submission forms and were consistent with the main website.
- Developed responsive HTML email templates which improved clickthrough rates by an average of 20%.

Teads Ltd - Designer / Frontend developer

Apr 2014 - Dec 2014

Worked in an agency environment as a Developer / Designer on small projects and microsites as well as static Photoshop templates and graphics for advertisement briefs.

- JavaScript, jQuery, GreenSock animation, Photoshop and Flash.
- Developed a boilerplate for standard video microsite with full video event tracking.
- Created Photoshop templates for full-screen takeover graphics that were distributed to global Teads branches.
- Designed numerous microsites serving various promotional purposes as part of larger marketing campaigns.

PROFILE

A seasoned Frontend developer with a keen eye for well designed, performant and elegant user experiences and interfaces. Expert in accessible, semantic markup and CSS from modern to legacy browsers. Solid understanding that a product should work well before it can look good, but that the overall brand aesthetic is still crucial. Well versed in modern JavaScript frameworks based on a solid foundation of core JavaScript understanding and a keen learning instinct. Proud owner of an unhealthy obsession with CSS.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) Computer Games Production (2:1)

2006 - 2009

Wide variety of modules covering design and technical skills. Focus on UI design and good UX practises. Advanced learning of industry standard software including but not limited to Photoshop, Illustrator, Maya and Web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript).

The Sixth Form College Farnborough (A-Levels)

2003 - 2005

Computing, English Language and Literature, Psychology

REFERENCES

Markus Happe - Exeon Analytics

Andrew Burden - Geeiq

Available on request

Available on request